# **Andrew Hoang**

Research in Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing

andrewhoang03@gmail.com (360) 878 – 6053

GitHub: andrew03 LinkedIn: hoang-andrew

Website: andrew03.github.io

## Summary

Deep learning researcher focused on Natural Language Processing and Computer Vision. 2+ years of experience in designing models to solve both research and application-based problems using Python coupled with PyTorch or TensorFlow. Passionate about solving interesting problems and learning something new.

### Education

## **University of Washington**

Seattle, WA

B.S. Computer Science (Data Science); GPA: 3.70

Sep 2016 – Jun 2019

Coursework: Computer Vision; Conversational AI; Deep Learning; Natural Language Processing;

Machine Learning; Data Visualization; Data Structures & Parallelism; Introduction to Data Management

Scholarships: Microsoft Endowed Scholarship, Washington Space Grant

## Technical Skills

Proficient: Python, C/C++, Java, JavaScript, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Git, Linux, Bash, Jupyter

Experience in: React, SQL, Ruby, Node.js, AWS, OpenCV

## Experience

Research Intern: Allen Institute of Artificial Intelligence

Oct 2018 - Jun 2019

- Currently working on visual common-sense reasoning
- ❖ Intern (30 hours a week) on the PRIOR team under Ali Farhadi focusing on high level computer vision research
- Designed seq2seq models and transformer models that achieved a score of 87% on the given task

Deep Learning (NLP & CV) Research Assistant: University of Washington

Mar 2017 – Present

- Currently working on applying transformer decoders to document summarization with policy learning
- Created an Image Captioning system using an encoder decoder model with attention in PyTorch
- ❖ Achieved a Bleu-4 score of 21.8 on MS COCO using VGG-16 with a LSTM and beam size of 10
- Added multiprocessing which decreased training and evaluation time by over 60%
- ❖ Implemented multi-layered bidirectional LSTMs for generation of cooking recipes in PyTorch

#### **Deep Learning (NLP & CV) Consultant:** Classify & Process

Feb 2018 – Present

- Currently working on designing autoencoders for image clustering
- Implemented Bi-LSTM CRF models for nested tagging in PyTorch achieving F1 scores of 0.9 on GENIA data set
- Constructed neural models for image segmentation in Pytorch using CNNS and fully connected CRFs
- Modified Al2 Extracting Scientific Figures from Text model for better generalization in non-scientific documents

## **Software Design Engineer Intern:** Pike 13

Jun 2017 – Sep 2017

- Built RESTful API endpoints and test suites for mobile application development using Ruby on Rails
- Discovered, ticketed, and fixed several web application UX bugs and documentation errors
- Improved client sign in iOS WebView application speed by 30% through the implementation of a React SPA

#### Wireless Security Research Assistant: University of Washington Bothell

Sep 2016 - Sep 2017

- Achieved 85% accuracy using time series analysis for anomaly detection in OpenCV and C++
- Condensed data using PCA and used mobile agents to drop overhead between IoT devices by over 40%
- ❖ Built CNN based Intrusion Detection Systems for IoT networks that got 60+% classification accuracy in PyTorch

#### **Projects**

### Mental Elf (Class)

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

- Created an Alexa skill focused discussing mental health and mental health advocacy in Python
- Designed a crawler for gathering information on mental health conditions and populating a DynamoDB table
- Processed response sentiment to determine FSM traversal for conversation topic shifts

## **Hashtag Generation (Class)**

May 2018 - Jun 2018

- Developed a seq2seg model and a multilabel classification model for hashtag generation in PyTorch
- Baselined the two models using hamming distance, achieving a minimum distance of 1.4 x 10-3
- Presented results in poster form and demoed models real time in a Jupyter notebook

### Emoji Talk (Hackathon)

Oct 2017

- ❖ Appended emojis to voice translated text for improved messaging in React and PyTorch
- Integrated Microsoft LUIS ASR API to get text translation from audio input
- Utilized sentiment analysis and entity extraction to append context appropriate emojis to the end of text

## Neural Net Chess (Personal)

Jan 2016 – Oct 2016

Adapted a feedforward neural network to play chess through reinforcement learning using TensorFlow